let us look at the solution for our
reliability and availability quiz we had
a hard disk that had three working
periods and three broken periods until
we threw it away the mean time to
failure is how long it works on average
before it breaks we had it working for
12 and then four and then 14 months so
on average it worked 12 plus four plus
14 months divided by 3 because there
were three failures in between and this
gives us 30 over 3 which is 10 so the
answer here is 10 months for a mean time
to repair its how long does it take to
repair it after a failure and we had a
one month eight two months and a
three-month repair period so our mttr is
simply 1 plus 2 plus 3 over 3 because we
need the average of these three which
ends up being two months and finally the
availability is what percentage of time
was this disk in service over the entire
period we can compute this in two ways
one is what's the mean time to failure /
mean time to failure plus mttr which
gives us 10 months of service on average
over 10 plus two months of both service
and repair this is 10 / 12 or 83 point
thirty three percent another way to
compute availability is to add up all
the months that we were in service and
divide them by the sum of all the months
all together in that case we would get
30 months of service / those same 30
months plus the six months of repair
which is 30 / 36 and this again gives us
our 83.3 three percent availability